

CHARLEY VAN DER KROGT

UX / UI DESIGNER (Amsterdam, NL)

SKILLS

USER RESEARCH

JOURNEY MAPPING

INFORMATION ARCHITECTURE

USABILITY ANALYSIS

USER TESTING

WIREFRAMING & PROTOTYPING

BRANDING & VISUAL DESIGN

COLOUR GRADING

VIDEOGRAPHY & EDITING

2D ANIMATION

SOFTWARE

FIGMA

SKETCH

INVISION

ADOBE SUITE

illustrator / photoshop / after effects / premiere pro

DA VINCI RESOLVE

BLENDER (BEGINNER)

ABOUT

Curious and analytically inclined videomaker - turned - UX / UI Designer with over 5 years of experience in digital & visual design.

Offering enthusiasm, an eye for visual design and a zest for solving complex problems. Seeking to use proven project management and design skills to improve or generate quality products that are intuitive and, most importantly, fun.

COMPETENCIES

RESULTS ORIENTATION

CURIOUS

ANALYTICAL

TEAM PLAYER

FAST LEARNER

OTHER JOBS

2nd CAMERA ASSISTANT / 2017 - 2018 freelance

SHOP ASSISTANT / 2018 - 2019 King Louie & Hester van Eeghen

EDUCATION

2019 - 2021 UX DESIGN (UI SPECIALIZATION)

CAREERFOUNDRY (ONLINE)

Topics: User-centric design principles, user research & testing, UI design patterns.

2014 - 2015 MA MEDIA STUDIES (TELEVISION & CROSS MEDIA CULTURE)

UNIVERSITY OF AMSTERDAM (AMSTERDAM, NL)

Topics: Mass media, digital communication, political economy of communication

2011 - 2014 BA (HONOURS) ILLUSTRATION & VISUAL MEDIA

UNIVERSITY OF THE ARTS LONDON (LONDON, UK)

Topics: Branding, visual strategy, design principles, production.

EXPERIENCE

VISITOR WELCOME & FRONT DESK - ANNE FRANK HOUSE / 2019 - 2020

- Customer-facing position: answering questions & solving problems visitors might have.
- Achievement: streamlining my response time, so I could serve 5000+ visitors a day & 100s of passersby
- Here I developed my interest in customer journeys & experiences.

VIDEOMAKER - HEARST NETHERLANDS / 2015 - 2017

- Developed video formats for brands such as Elle, Cosmopolitan and Esquire.
- Lead studio shoots with big teams (10+) for clients such as Triumph and Maybelline.
- Colleagues consistently complimented me on visual design & colour grading skills.

VIDEOMAKER - FREELANCE / 2015 - ONGOING

- All-rounder: jobs including interviewing, editing, colour grading and camera & lighting operation.
- Master at calming interviewees' nerves.
- Focused on streamlining big chunks of (sometimes complicated) information into core concepts.
- Used to writing pitches, storyboards and scripts.